BRAD RICHARD WILL

SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

Ingenious, **Determined**, and **Self-motivated** senior software engineer with 9 years of professional experience who always works as a self-starter, with strong experience in the architecture, development, and maintenance of a wide variety of software. Experienced in the development of a diverse set of products and technologies, which includes e-commerce, NFT marketplaces, performance monitoring/tuning, operating systems, system configuration, groupware, GUI, spreadsheets, database, and **blockchain** related products, with a deep and clear understanding about full-stack application development and **SDLC**. Have great learning attitudes, and always trying to learn more and more.



brad.will0715@gmail.com



S live:.cid.525d20d740ed023d

2 1024 2nd St W, Birmingham, AL 35204, United States

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Angular.js
- Vue.js
- Next.js
- Node.js
- Express.js
- Nest.js
- Golang

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCER

Upwork, Guru and Freelancer

May 2022 - Current

 Major in blockchain related projects like NFT marketplace, DeFi, and DAO projects as a Senior Blockchain & Fullstack developer.

SR BLOCKCHAIN & FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Coincheck

Nov 2019 - May 2022

- Managed a geographically distributed team of 8 developers with operations, priorities, and development goals utilizing Agile techniques such as weekly/bi-weekly scrums.
- Experience in architecture and coding of enterprise-grade decentralized applications.
- Developed scalable applications using the MEAN stack and created POCs for rest service development using Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Wrote smart contracts for decentralized applications and audited 100+ smart contracts.
- Strong experience with **Unit Test** and **E2E** Test.

- MongoDB
- MariaDB
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- GraphDB
- Oracle
- DvnamoDB
- ElasticSearch
- Solidity
- Rust
- Ethereum
- Binance Smart Chain
- Solana
- DEX
- DeFi
- DAO
- Truffle, Hardhat
- Amazone Web Service
- Microsoft Azure
- Heroku / Netlify / Vercel
- Firebase
- Github / Gitlab
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- · Agile Methodology

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE

California State University 2012 - 2016

INTERESTS

READING BOOKS

BUNGE JUMPINIG

- Functional specification reviews to ensure consistency and accuracy with the client's needs
- Collaborated with external programmers to coordinate the delivery of 6 new software applications.
- Developed and deployed smart contracts for Token Bridge, DeFi,
 NFT marketplace, NFT minting, and Crypto exchange utilizing
 Web3.js, Solidity, and Rust.

BLOCKCHAIN & FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Moontek

Jun 2018 -Sep 2019

- Understand business drivers, goals/objectives, and opportunities and create innovative strategy/vision and solution roadmap/architecture for the implementation.
- Experienced with multiple Blockchain Technology platforms (Ethereum/Hyperledger/Ripple/Solana).
- Work with MERN, MEAN, and MEVN stack for developing applications.
- Responsible for creating Restful web services to server data to the front-end application in JSON format
- Developed hundreds of **smart contracts** deployed on the main net, and audited 100+.
- Redesigned the company site and built it.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Oasis Web Asia

Sep 2016 - May 2018

- Analyzed business requirements to translate functional requirements into technical requirements and developed web applications using MongoDB, Express, and Golang,
- Participated in 300+ code reviews to ensure code quality and receive mentoring from senior developers.
- Gained experience with various web development tools including Bower, NPM, Git, Material design, Gulp, and cloud services like AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku, and so on.
- Applied hands-on learning and agile development to build full MERN stack applications.
- Developed Unit and E2E test cases using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha, Grunt, Node.js.
- Redesigned and rebuilt 30+ Company's websites, and resulted in remarkable growth in 10+ startup companies

TOP PROUD PROJECTS

https://www.ehecatldragon.com/home

https://market.solanamonkey.business/

https://dongletrade.com

https://niftydudes.com/

https://www.247legalassist.com/

https://www.lawprentice.com/